Tulasi Gayatri Madeti Web developer

https://in.linkedin.com/tulasigayathri

Mobile: +919849478238

tulasi.gayathri@gmail.com

Summary of Experience:

Gayathri is Web developer with 8+ years of experience in technologies PHP, .NET and Ruby on Rails. She actively participated in developing standalone software and web applications for multiple database platforms. She has been working in various stages of the software development life cycle requirement gathering, analysis of the product, participated and played a key role in designing the key features of the product also participated in development. She has a good attention to detail and able to handle modules independently.

She is a good team player with excellent communication and organization skills having critical problem solving abilities, deep sense of commitment to perfect work. She is gifted with presence of mind, logical thinking, enthusiastic and hardworking

Areas of expertise include:

- Frontend Development (HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap)
- Asp .NET, c#
- PHP
- MYSQL
- SQL Server
- Javascript & Jquery
- Wordpress, Joomla

Educational Qualification:

- Masters degree from Nagarjuna University
- Bachelor in Computer Applications.

Employment History:

- Techmahindra SMART Academy (May-2017 – Till Date
- > Istar (Sep-2017 to May -2017)
- Icentris software development (Sept 2011 – October 2015)
- Unique-e-solutions (Feb 2011Sep 2011)
- Vega Prosys (July 2008 Oct 2011)
- Infronics (Feb 2008 June 2008)
- Shiftwave info technologies (Jan 2007 – June 20007)
- Cooptions technologies. (May 2006 to Feb 2007)

Selected Projects:

Techmahindra Foundation

May 2017 - Till Date

- Responsible for developing intranet applications for the academy.
- Have taken the requirements, analysis and designed the application.
- Responsible for training students on frontend development and web development.
- Have participated in counselling the students.
- · Participated in selection process.
- Also responsible for necessary document verification

Transcriber Desktop Techlead

July 2015 - October 2016

- Responsible for managing a team of skilled developers to develop the workflow.
- Communicated with onsite PM to discuss road map and the priority items.
- Prepared release schedule and made sure the release is made on time and bugs free.
- Had the responsibility to make deployments to the server for releases.

1

- Effectively communicate and document technical analyses and results.
- Discussed with various clients of the product, consolidated the requirements gave solutions to automate the manula process of transcription and handing complex scenarios like addendums.

Vibe March 2013 – June 2015

- Actively participated in development of various modules in the project.
- Extensively used various gems like devise, spree etc and integrated them with the current project.
- Collaborated with QA team and the business analyst to discuss the requirements, workflow and finalized the design.
- Have made continual improvement to code by refactoring old legacy code
- Conduct peer review and provided feedback
- Reported the status with alarms, explanations and solutions. Promptly escalated the issues to the reporting manager, track and resolve issues

Unity

September 2011 - Feb 2013

- Responsible for making changes to the existing features..
- Working closely with the project manager and discuss in detail about change orders and requested changes by the client.
- Responsible for giving time estimates.
- Used c#. Javascript and Jquery extensively and also used HTML5 to make the application responsive.
- Helped PM in the annual and mid-year appraisal process.

Telecom

Client: Unique-e-solutions

February 2011 - August 2011

- Gathered information on how to improve the quality of the data..
- Participated in discussions and modified the workflow of the application to improve the data validation.
- Managed the Design trends team to help inform seasonal themes from a macro-consumer trends perspective.
- Collaborate and establish relationships with quality team to achieve the data quality.
- Fixed numerous bugs in sql server stored procedures in the application.

EZSMS Developer

February 2008 - June 2008

- As a developer involved in fixing various complex bugs.
- Played a good team player and participated in the development.

PAX

Developer

September 2006 - January 2007

- As a developer involved in fixing various complex bugs.
- Played a good team player and participated in the development.

Timesheet management system Developer

May 2006 - August 2006

- As a developer involved in fixing various complex bugs.
- Played a good team player and participated in the development.

Specialties: Specialized in Web development and expertise in Client-Server based applications developed using c#, asp.net, ROR and PHP. Also developed reusable business objects in various industries like healthcare and direct sales software etc. Thorough knowledge of object oriented analysis and design and N-tier architecture. Strong in front-end GUI development using ASP.Net, ASP,

HTML, JavaScript, jquery etc. Strong in backend database development including designing and administering databases, writing stored procedures, SQL and triggers for SQL Server databases. Thorough knowledge in ORM and active record techniques. Strong in Business requirement analysis and functional specification design and documentation. Strong analytical skills. And strong oral and written communication skills.

Technical Skills:

Software tools/skills: C#, ASP.NET, PHP, ROR, Visio, MS Word, Excel

Databases: SQL, MYSQL, MongoDB.

Operating System: Windows, Ubuntu

Version control tools: Visual source safe, SVN and Github

Other: HTML, JavaScript, jquery